<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">
  <!-- insert your AIML categories here -->
  <category>
    <pattern>WHAT DO YOU KNOW ABOUT</pattern>
    <template>A lot, Should I tell you a fact?</template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>YES</pattern>
    <that>A LOT, SHOULD I TELL YOU A FACT?</that>
    <template>
      <srai>FACTS</srai>
    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>TELL ME A FACT</pattern>
    <template>
      <srai>FACTS</srai>
    </template>
  </category>
  <category>
    <pattern>FACTS</pattern>
    <template>
      <random>
        <li>The speed of light is generally rounded down to 186,000
        miles per second. In exact terms it is 299,792,458
        m/s.</li>
        <li>It takes 8 minutes 17 seconds for light to travel from
        the Sun’s surface to the Earth.</li>
        <li>October 12th, 1999 was declared “The Day of Six
        Billion” based on United Nations projections.</li>
        <li>10 percent of all human beings ever born are alive at
        this very moment.</li>
        <li>The Earth spins at 1,000 mph but it travels through
        space at an incredible 67,000 mph.</li>
        <li>Every year over one million earthquakes shake the
        Earth.</li>
        <li>When Krakatoa erupted in 1883, its force was so great
        it could be heard 4,800 kilometres away in Australia.</li>
        <li>The largest ever hailstone weighed over 1kg and fell in
        Bangladesh in 1986.</li>
        <li>Every second around 100 lightning bolts strike the
        Earth.</li>
        <li>Every year lightning kills 1000 people.</li>
        <li>In October 1999 an Iceberg the size of London broke
        free from the Antarctic ice shelf .</li>
        <li>If you could drive your car straight up you would
        arrive in space in just over an hour.</li>
        <li>Human tapeworms can grow up to 22.9m.</li>
        <li>The Earth is 4.56 billion years old...the same age as
        the Moon and the Sun.</li>
        <li>The dinosaurs became extinct before the Rockies or the
        Alps were formed.</li>
        <li>Female black widow spiders eat their males after
        mating.</li>
        <li>When a flea jumps, the rate of acceleration is 20 times
        that of the space shuttle during launch.</li>
        <li>If our Sun were just inch in diameter, the nearest star
        would be 445 miles away.</li>
        <li>The Australian billygoat plum contains 100 times more
        vitamin C than an orange.</li>
        <li>Astronauts cannot belch – there is no gravity to
        separate liquid from gas in their stomachs.</li>
        <li>The air at the summit of Mount Everest, 29,029 feet is
        only a third as thick as the air at sea level.</li>
        <li>One million, million, million, million, millionth of a
        second after the Big Bang the Universe was the size of a
        ...pea.</li>
        <li>DNA was first discovered in 1869 by Swiss Friedrich
        Mieschler.</li>
        <li>The molecular structure of DNA was first determined by
        Watson and Crick in 1953.</li>
        <li>The first synthetic human chromosome was constructed by
        US scientists in 1997.</li>
        <li>The thermometer was invented in 1607 by Galileo.</li>
        <li>Englishman Roger Bacon invented the magnifying glass in
        1250.</li>
        <li>Alfred Nobel invented dynamite in 1866.</li>
        <li>Wilhelm Rontgen won the first Nobel Prize for physics
        for discovering X-rays in 1895.</li>
        <li>The tallest tree ever was an Australian eucalyptus – In
        1872 it was measured at 435 feet tall.</li>
        <li>Christian Barnard performed the first heart transplant
        in 1967 – the patient lived for 18 days.</li>
        <li>The wingspan of a Boeing 747 is longer than the Wright
        brother’s first flight.</li>
        <li>An electric eel can produce a shock of up to 650
        volts.</li>
        <li>‘Wireless’ communications took a giant leap forward in
        1962 with the launch of Telstar, the first satellite
        capable of relaying telephone and satellite TV
        signals.</li>
        <li>The earliest wine makers lived in Egypt around 2300
        BC.</li>
        <li>The Ebola virus kills 4 out of every 5 humans it
        infects.</li>
        <li>In 5 billion years the Sun will run out of fuel and
        turn into a Red Giant.</li>
        <li>Giraffes often sleep for only 20 minutes in any 24
        hours. They may sleep up to 2 hours (in spurts – not all at
        once), but this is rare. They never lie down.</li>
        <li>A pig’s orgasm lasts for 30 minutes.</li>
        <li>Without its lining of mucus your stomach would digest
        itself.</li>
        <li>Humans have 46 chromosomes, peas have 14 and crayfish
        have 200.</li>
        <li>There are 60,000 miles of blood vessels in the human
        body.</li>
        <li>An individual blood cell takes about 60 seconds to make
        a complete circuit of the body.</li>
        <li>Utopia ia a large, smooth lying area of Mars.</li>
        <li>On the day that Alexander Graham Bell was buried the
        entire US telephone system was shut down for 1 minute in
        tribute.</li>
        <li>The low frequency call of the humpback whale is the
        loudest noise made by a living creature.</li>
        <li>The call of the humpback whale is louder than Concorde
        and can be heard from 500 miles away.</li>
        <li>A quarter of the world’s plants are threatened with
        extinction by the year 2010.</li>
        <li>Each person sheds 40lbs of skin in his or her
        lifetime.</li>
        <li>At 15 inches the eyes of giant squids are the largest
        on the planet.</li>
        <li>The largest galexies contain a million, million
        stars.</li>
        <li>The Universe contains over 100 billion galaxies.</li>
        <li>Wounds infested with maggots heal quickly and without
        spread of gangrene or other infection.</li>
        <li>More germs are transferred shaking hands than
        kissing.</li>
        <li>The longest glacier in Antarctica, the Almbert glacier,
        is 250 miles long and 40 miles wide.</li>
        <li>The fastest speed a falling raindrop can hit you is
        18mph.</li>
        <li>A healthy person has 6,000 million, million, million
        haemoglobin molecules.</li>
        <li>A salmon-rich, low cholesterol diet means that Inuits
        rarely suffer from heart disease.</li>
        <li>Inbreeding causes 3 out of every 10 Dalmation dogs to
        suffer from hearing disability.</li>
        <li>The world’s smallest winged insect, the Tanzanian
        parasitic wasp, is smaller than the eye of a housefly.</li>
        <li>If the Sun were the size of a beach ball then Jupiter
        would be the size of a golf ball and the Earth would be as
        small as a pea.</li>
        <li>It would take over an hour for a heavy object to sink
        6.7 miles down to the deepest part of the ocean.</li>
        <li>There are more living organisms on the skin of each
        human than there are humans on the surface of the
        earth.</li>
        <li>The grey whale migrates 12,500 miles from the Artic to
        Mexico and back every year.</li>
        <li>Each rubber molecule is made of 65,000 individual
        atoms.</li>
        <li>Around a million, billion neutrinos from the Sun will
        pass through your body while you read this sentence...and
        now they are already past the Moon.</li>
        <li>Quasars emit more energy than 100 giant galaxies.</li>
        <li>Quasars are the most distant objects in the
        Universe.</li>
        <li>The saturn V rocket which carried man to the Moon
        develops power equivalent to fifty 747 jumbo jets.</li>
        <li>Koalas sleep an average of 22 hours a day, two hours
        more than the sloth.</li>
        <li>Light would take .13 seconds to travel around the
        Earth.</li>
        <li>Males produce one thousand sperm cells each second – 86
        million each day.</li>
        <li>Neutron stars are so dense that a teaspoonful would
        weigh more than all the people on Earth.</li>
        <li>One in every 2000 babies is born with a tooth.</li>
        <li>Every hour the Universe expands by a billion miles in
        all directions.</li>
        <li>Somewhere in the flicker of a badly tuned TV set is the
        background radiation from the Big Bang.</li>
        <li>Even travelling at the speed of light it would take 2
        million years to reach the nearest large galaxy,
        Andromeda.</li>
        <li>The temperature in Antarctica plummets as low as -35
        degrees celsius.</li>
        <li>At over 2000 kilometres long The Great Barrier Reef is
        the largest living structure on Earth.</li>
        <li>A thimbleful of a neutron star would weigh over 100
        million tons.</li>
        <li>The risk of being struck by a falling meteorite for a
        human is one occurence every 9,300 years.</li>
        <li>The driest inhabited place in the world is Aswan, Egypt
        where the annual average rainfall is .02 inches.</li>
        <li>The deepest part of any ocean in the world is the
        Mariana trench in the Pacific with a depth of 35,797
        feet.</li>
        <li>The largest meteorite craters in the world are in
        Sudbury, Ontario, canada and in Vredefort, South
        Africa.</li>
        <li>The largest desert in the world, the Sahara, is
        3,500,000 square miles.</li>
        <li>The largest dinosaur ever discovered was Seismosaurus
        who was over 100 feet long and weighed up to 80
        tonnes.</li>
        <li>The African Elephant gestates for 22 months.</li>
        <li>The short-nosed Bandicoot has a gestation period of
        only 12 days.</li>
        <li>The mortality rate if bitten by a Black Mamba snake is
        over 95%.</li>
        <li>In the 14th century the Black Death killed 75,000,000
        people. It was carried by fleas on the black rat.</li>
        <li>A dog’s sense of smell is 1,000 times more sensitive
        than a humans.</li>
        <li>A typical hurricane produces the nergy equivalent to
        8,000 one megaton bombs.</li>
        <li>90% of those who die from hurricanes die from
        drowning.</li>
        <li>To escape the Earth’s gravity a rocket need to travel
        at 7 miles a second.</li>
        <li>If every star in the Milky Way was a grain of salt they
        would fill an Olympic sized swimming pool.</li>
        <li>Microbial life can survive on the cooling rods of a
        nuclear reactor.</li>
        <li>Micro-organisms have been brought back to life after
        being frozen in perma-frost for three million years.</li>
        <li>Our oldest radio broadcasts of the 1930s have already
        travelled past 100,000 stars.</li>
        <li>Butterflies cannot fly if their body temperature is
        less than 86 degrees.</li>
        <li>Neurons multiply at a rate 250,000 neurons per minute
        during early pregnancy.</li>
        <li>Elephants have the longest pregnancy in the animal
        kingdom at 22 months. The longest human pregnancy on record
        is 17 months, 11 days.</li>
        <li>A female oyster produces 100 million young in her
        lifetime, the typical hen lays 19 dozen eggs a year, and it
        is possible for one female cat to be responsible for the
        birth of 20,736 kittens in four years. Michelle Druggar
        holds the record for largest human family, having given
        birth to 17 children.</li>
        <li>750ml of blood pumps through your brain every minute
        which is 15-20% of blood flow from the heart.</li>
        <li>The human brain is about 75% water.</li>
        <li>Dragonflies are capable of flying sixty miles per hour,
        making them one of the fastest insects. This is good since
        they are in a big hurry, as they only live about
        twenty-four hours.</li>
        <li>Flies jump backwards during takeoff.</li>
        <li>A housefly will regurgitate its food and eat it
        again.</li>
        <li>Termites outweigh humans by almost ten to one.</li>
        <li>A spider's web is not a home, but rather a trap for its
        food. They are as individual as snowflakes, with no two
        ever being the same. Some tropical spiders have built webs
        over eighteen feet across.</li>
        <li>More people are afraid of spiders than death.
        Amazingly, few people are afraid of Champagne corks even
        though you are more likely to be killed by one than by a
        spider.</li>
        <li>Your brain consumes 25 watts of power while you’re
        awake. This amount of energy is enough to illuminate a
        lightbulb.</li>
        <li>It is impossible to lick your elbow.</li>
        <li>Intelligent people have more zinc and copper in their
        hair.</li>
        <li>In every episode of Seinfeld there is a Superman
        somewhere.</li>
        <li>Possums have one of the shortest pregnancies at 16
        days. The shortest human pregnancy to produce a healthy
        baby was 22 weeks, 6 days -- the baby was the length of a
        ballpoint pen.</li>
        <li>Wearing headphones for just an hour will increase the
        bacteria in your ear by 700 times.</li>
        <li>The most poisonous spider is the black widow. Its venom
        is more potent than a rattlesnake's.</li>
        <li>13% of Americans actually believe that some parts of
        the moon are made of cheese.</li>
        <li>The world's youngest parents were 8 and 9 and lived in
        China in 1910.</li>
        <li>Fish that live more than 800 meters below the ocean
        surface don't have eyes.</li>
        <li>Butterflies range in size from a tiny 1/8 inch to a
        huge almost 12 inches.</li>
        <li>Some Case Moth caterpillars (Psychidae) build a case
        around themselves that they always carry with them. It is
        made of silk and pieces of plants or soil.</li>
        <li>Most household dust is made of dead skin cells.</li>
        <li>One in eight million people has progeria, a disease
        that causes people to grow faster than they age.</li>
        <li>The male seahorse carries the eggs until they hatch
        instead of the female.</li>
        <li>Negative emotions such as anxiety and depression can
        weaken your immune system.</li>
        <li>Stephen Hawking was born exactly 300 years after
        Galileo died.</li>
        <li>Mercury is the only planet whose orbit is coplanar with
        its equator.</li>
        <li>The Morgan's Sphinx Moth from Madagascar has a
        proboscis (tube mouth) that is 12 to 14 inches long to get
        the nectar from the bottom of a 12 inch deep orchid
        discovered by Charles Darwin.</li>
        <li>Some moths never eat anything as adults because they
        don't have mouths. They must live on the energy they stored
        as caterpillars.</li>
        <li>In 1958 Entomologist W.G. Bruce published a list of
        Arthropod references in the Bible. The most frequently
        named bugs from the Bible are: Locust: 24, Moth: 11,
        Grasshopper: 10, Scorpion: 10, Caterpillar: 9, and Bee:
        4.</li>
        <li>People eat insects – called "Entomophagy"(people eating
        bugs) – it has been practiced for centuries throughout
        Africa, Australia, Asia, the Middle East, and North,
        Central and South America. Why? Because many bugs are both
        protein-rich and good sources of vitamins, minerals and
        fats.</li>
        <li>Grapes explode when you put them in the microwave. Go
        on, try it then</li>
        <li>Benjamin Franklin was the fifth in a series of the
        youngest son of the youngest son.</li>
        <li>Triskaidekaphobia means fear of the number 13.</li>
        <li>Paraskevidekatriaphobia means fear of Friday the 13th,
        which occurs one to three times a year.</li>
        <li>In Italy, 17 is considered an unlucky number. In Japan,
        4 is considered an unlucky number.</li>
        <li>A female ferret will die if it goes into heat and
        cannot find a mate.</li>
        <li>In ancient Rome, when a man testified in court he would
        swear on his testicles.</li>
        <li>The ZIP in “ZIP code” means Zoning Improvement
        Plan.</li>
        <li>Coca-Cola contained Coca (whose active ingredient is
        cocaine) from 1885 to 1903.</li>
        <li>A “2 by 4" is really 1 1/2 by 3 1/2.</li>
      </random>
    </template>
  </category>
</aiml>
